准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
赢家通吃热狗
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
稍等
Hold on
就快好了
Coming right up
马上来
Now
再等一下
Give me a second
上菜上菜上菜
Order up, up, up
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward
你怎么还没去倒垃圾
Why haven't you taken out the trash?
我都忙不过来了  蟹老板
I'm swamped, Mr. Krabs
你干嘛披着毛巾
Why are you wearing a towel?
一眼都能看得出来我在蒸桑拿
Well, obviously, I was in me sauna
当经理可辛苦了  知道不
Being a manager is hard work, you know?
你表现得再好点才行
You have to do better
你就不能帮我一下吗
Can't you help me a little bit?
经理才不做脏活累活
A manager does not do grunt work
那可是章鱼哥这种员工的任务
That's what Squidwards are for
我理应当上经理  整天无所事事才对
I deserve to be manager and sit on my butt all day
但我有机会升职吗
But will I ever get promoted?
你已经当废物当烦了吗
Are you tired of being a loser?
对
Yes
等等  谁在说话
Wait, who said that?
你就不想当个废热狗吗
Wouldn't you rather be a weenie?
不怎么想
Not exactly
废热狗儿童乐园正在招募经理
Weenie Hut Jr's is now hiring managers
儿童乐园
经理
你的职务将包括
Your responsibilities will include
放松享清福  让机器人
Kicking back, relaxing, and letting robots
把脏活累活都做了
do all of the grunt work
太强了
Righteous
快来儿童乐园找工作
Apply now to Weenie Hut Jr.'s
成为我们这家企业机器的关键齿轮
and become a pivotal cog in the corporate machine
经理
A manager?
正合我意
That's for me
再见了  蟹堡王
So long, Krusty Krab
再见了
So long
那个该死的收银员呢
Where is that blasted cashier?
已经迟到一小时了
He's already an hour late
这个老太婆谁啊
And who the heck is this old lady?
我闻到了腌椰菜味
I smell pickles
蟹老板  你不觉得章鱼哥
Mr. Krabs, isn't Squidward
这些天帅气得不得吗
looking better than ever these days?
什么
What?
那又不是章鱼哥
That ain't Squidward
不是吗
It's not?
她怎么戴着章鱼哥的帽子
Why is she wearing his hat?
章鱼哥哪去了
Where is he?
他失踪了吗
Is he lost?
他怎么会迟到这么久
Why is he so late?
章鱼哥
Squidward
我来找你了
I'm coming to find you
章鱼哥
Squidward
儿童乐园
好
Yeah
章鱼哥
Squidward
找到你可真高兴
I'm so glad I found you
来带你回到蟹堡王去吧
Now, let's get you back to the Krusty Krab
那可不行
I don't think so
我绝对不可能回到蟹堡王去
I'm not going back to the Krusty Krab ever
因为我现在是这企业机器的关键齿轮
Because now I am a pivotal cog in the corporate machine
不会吧
Oh, no
听起来感觉很糟糕啊
That sounds horrible
不会的
Oh, no
听起来我就是这里的经理
It sounds like I'm the manager here
经理
也就是说我可以来决定
Which also means I decide
谁能留  谁不能留
who stays and who goes
废热狗机器人
Weenie Bots
把这个乌合之众踢出去
Kick out this riffraff
得令  废热狗
As you command, Weenie
听好了  废热狗机器人
Attention, Weenie Bots
身为你们新任的经理
As your new manager
我要在此做出一些改变
I'll be making a few changes around here
点唱机里的所有音乐全都要换成
All music in the jukebox will now be
轻柔爵士
smooth jazz
所有废热狗主题作品
All Weenie-themed art
全都要换成艺术作品
will now be fine art
最后  无论如何
And, lastly, under no circumstances
都不准有谁打断我的经理时间
is anyone allowed to interrupt my manager time
当经理可辛苦了
Being a manager is hard work
废热狗老板  你得出去倒垃圾
Boss Weenie, you must take out the trash
你为什么不倒
Why can't you do it?
我的扩展电源线够不到
My extension cord won't reach
还是要好过
Still better
那个蟹堡
Than the Krusty
王
Krab
开门啊
Open that door
万岁
Hooray
庆祝
Celebration
真好
Good
你回来了
You are back
废热狗
Weenie
好了  章鱼哥
All right, Squidward
该来做点经理工作了
It's time for a little managerial work
如何修理无法无天的机器人
"How to Repair Unruly Robots"
如何修理
无法无天的机器人
那样应该就行了
That ought to do the trick
废热狗机器人  给我个热狗
Weenie Bots, bring me a weenie
是  经理先生
Yes, Mr. Manager
成功了
I did it
他们变成完美员工了
They're perfect employees now
废热狗机器人  管店
Weenie Bots, run the store
我要独享经理时间去了
I'm having manager time
是  经理先生
Yes, Mr. Manager
双童周三
经理先生
Mr. Manager
看不出来我在睡觉吗
Can't you see I'm trying to sleep?
我是说负责经理
I mean manage
废热狗儿童乐园公司总裁要来了
The president
of the Weenie Hut Corporation is arriving
怎么不早说
Why didn't you say so?
好个废热狗
What a weenie
热狗小狗热
Weenie J. Weiner
小表示的是儿童
The J stands for Junior
你一定就是章鱼哥了
You must be Squidward Q. Tentacles
哥表示的是大哥
The Q stands for Quincy
有何贵干
To what do I owe this honor?
你大获成功  引起了总部的热议
Your success has been all the buzz
down at headquarters
所以我就过来给你升职
So I came straightaway to offer you the big promotion
总算有人能认可我的价值了
Finally, someone recognizes my worth
不过你得先参加一下
But, first, you'll need to take
高级经理培训
our upper-management course
请登上我的废热狗直升机
Please, step into my weeniecopter
欢迎光临废热狗成年乐园
Welcome to Weenie Hut Senior's
恭喜你  废热狗
Congratulations, Weenie
这边有好多机器人在工作啊
There sure are a lot of robots working here
没错  机器人更加高效
Yes, robots are so much more efficient
更加卫生
and sanitary
欢迎光临  废热狗
Welcome, Weenie
请坐下吧
Please, have a seat
躺平  脑袋只想着热狗
Now lie back and think of weenies
这是个什么经理培训啊
What exactly is this management course?
告诉你吧  章鱼哥
Well, you see, Squidward
我们要把你变成
we are going to turn you
你能力范围中最为高效的经理
into the most efficient manager you can be
也就是要把你变成
By turning you into a
机器人
Robot
机器人啊
Oh, a robot
一听就很
well, that sounds just--
救命
Help me
我们这就是在救你啊  章鱼哥
We are helping you, Squidward
你会成为
You will be
我们的一员
One of us
果不其然
Typical
你好啊  章鱼哥
Ahoy there, Squidward
我们来救你了
We're here to save you
你们怎么会知道我在这里
How did you even know I was here?
我知道你有危险
I knew you were in danger
我都起章鱼感应了
My squiddy sense was tingling
我不想知道那什么意思
I don't want to know what that means
快救我出去啊
Just get me out of here
海绵宝宝  装载炮弹
All right, SpongeBob, load her up
她准备好了
She's ready
小心你的头
Watch your head
夹啊夹
Pinchy, pinchy
可爱可爱可爱可爱
Cutie, cutie, cutie, cutie
那个婴儿宝宝要炸了
That brat's gonna burst
好吃的热狗
Yummy weenie
看来我们正好赶到了
Looks like we got here just in time
很高兴再见到你  兄弟
Good to see ya, pal
上菜了  章鱼哥
Order up, Squidward
你能回来真是太棒了
Gee, it sure is great to have you back
唉
Sigh
拜托拔了我电源吧
Please unplug me
困在电梯里
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
灵感的肚皮就蕴藏在你的勇气中
"The belly of inspiration lies in the midst of your gut"
最好把这本好书还给图书馆
Welp, I better return
this wonderful book to the library
免得逾期了
before it's due
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
站得太靠近的事我是怎么说的
what did I tell you about standing too close to me?
你说了
You said
如果你一直要站得太靠近我
If you keep standing too close to me
我就会被你绊倒
I'm going to trip over you
不必多言
I rest my case
更不必变脸
and my face
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squidward
我只想邀请你跟我和派大星一起出游
I just wanted to invite you to go with me and Patrick
我们今天的安排可好玩了
We have a really fun day planned
真的是好厉害啊
Shucks and golly gee
我真希望能来
I really wish I could come
跟你和派大星玩得特开心
and have big fun with you and Patrick
但是呢
But?
但是我得把我最爱的每日金句书
But I have to return
my favorite book of daily affirmations
赶在中午之前还给图书馆
to the library by noon
不然就得受罚
or I'll have to pay a penalty
你是说这本书吗
You mean this book?
生活中  与树木捉迷藏
"In life, 'tis better to play hide-and-seek with the trees
优于与微风下棋
than checkers with the wind"
派大星就会说这种金句
That's what Patrick always says
才不会
No, he doesn't
自个找金句去吧
Get your own affirmations
欢乐时光
快艇
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
出发了
Here we go
图书馆
早上九点
9:00 a.m.--
离到期还早着呢
plenty of time before the deadline
没错  得早起才可以早来
Yeah, you have to get up pretty early in the morning
而我也早起了
And I did
找到了
There it is--
还书处  顶层
book returns, top floor
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
要上楼吗
Going up?
搭下趟得了
I'll take the next one
章鱼哥
Squidward
挡门啊
Hold the door
关门啊
Close the door
谢谢你帮忙挡门  章鱼哥
Thanks for holding the door, Squidward
你们俩白痴今天不是有啥好玩安排吗
I thought you yo-yos had a big day of fun planned
怎么不玩了
Why aren't you there?
我们就在玩啊  章鱼哥
We are there, Squidward
因为今天是
because today is
坐电梯日
Elevator Riding Day
我虽怒火中烧
I feel my anger
但又如一盘意大利扁面一般冷静
But I am calm like a plate of linguine
派大星  麻烦你
Patrick, be a dear
给我按一下顶层的按钮
and hit the top-floor button for me, please
顶层
Top floor
上楼
Going up--
先把其他楼的按钮都按了再说
right after we hit all these other floors
你在干什么
What are you doing?
对啊  派大星
Yeah, Patrick
你在干什么
what are you doing?
少按了一颗
You missed one
一层都不能落
Every floor counts
先上顶楼
Top floor first
不好了  我们被困了
Oh, no, we're trapped
困得跟沙丁鱼似的
trapped like sardines
没事的  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我们向来都出这种事的
This happens to us all the time
对啊  上周咱就只等了五小时
Yeah, last week we only had to wait five hours
五小时
"Five hours"?
都已经超过还书期限了
That's past the book-return deadline
如一盘意大利扁面一般
Like a plate of linguine
不然就打一下紧急电话
Why don't we just use the emergency phone
来求救吧
and call for help?
你想从简就从简吧
Well, if you want to do it the easy way
喂
Hello?
Hello
感谢海神王
Thank Neptune
没想到这电话居然还能用
I didn't think this phone would work
我被困在电梯里了
I'm trapped in an elevator
别学我说话
Stop saying what I'm saying
我真被困在电梯里了
I really am trapped in an elevator
天啊
Gosh
你一点忙都帮不上
You're no help at all
白痴
Idiot
放松是跃向宁静的脚尖
"Relaxation is the tippy toe to tranquility"
你就放松吧
Now you relax
派大星修得好
Patrick can fix it
对啊  我爸当过一整天的电梯医生
Yeah, my dad was an elevator surgeon for a whole day
他当过什么了
He was a what?
螺丝刀
Screwdriver
现在来接上正确的线
And now to connect the right wires
不是这根
That's not it
等等
Wait
派大星  不要
Patrick, don't
派大星
Patrick
够了
Enough
快放我出去
Get me out of here
这破门怎么就是不开
Why won't these stupid doors open?
章鱼哥
Squidward
抓住我的手
Grab my hand
真是好险啊  对吧章鱼哥
That was a close one, huh, Squidward?
那是什么
What's that?
一扇门
A door
快点
Hurry
祝你们好运  废物
Good luck, losers
谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
那本书总算可以按时归还了
Finally, that book is getting returned on time
感谢海神王
Thank Neptune
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
你回来了
You're back
给我们推一把吧
Now give us a boost
平静心境浮于奶酪之海
"Serenity floats on an ocean of cheese"
我饿坏了
I'm starving
我们被困多久了
How long have we been stuck in here?
放心  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
你不在电梯那会儿  我们订了匹萨
While you were out, I ordered a pizza
快给我  你这白痴
Give me that, you pea brain
可以打电话求救
We can call for help
披萨馋嘴
有送必达
果然如此
Of course
匹萨外卖
Pizza delivery
谢了
Thanks
我们得救了
We're saved
派大星
Patrick
好耶
All right
开吃吧
Let's eat
吃什么
Eat what?
这下我要饿死了  书也要逾期了
Now I'm starving, and my book is going to be late
仅当失去了一切  方能看清鼻孔
"Only when all is lost can you see inside your nostrils
找寻自己的内心
and find yourself"
经历了很久的宁静之后
我自由了
I'm free
历经22年
After 22 years
总算逃出那间该死的电梯了
I finally got out of that cursed elevator
什么
W-what?
又一间电梯
Another elevator?
你好  陌生人
Greetings, stranger
欢迎光临我们的宁静之岛
Welcome to our island of tranquility
上楼
Going up
比我先前的电梯好上个不少
This is a lot nicer than my old elevator
介意我待一会儿吗
Mind if I stay here a while?
你得问问大王
You'll have to ask the king
上楼
Going up
大王
The king?
有谁呼唤我的大名
Did someone say my name?
睿智的章鱼哥大王啊
Oh, wise King Squidward
这位疲惫的旅人期望能与我们暂留
This weary traveler wishes to stay with us
拜托了  大王
Please, King
能留下他吗
can we keep him?
让我查查书
Let me consult the book
书
The book
患难见忠仆
"A friend in need is a servant guaranteed"
书同意你留下
The book says yes
上楼
Going up
你当然可以与我们暂留  我的孩子
Of course you can stay with us, my child
我们会向你传授书中之道
We'll teach you the ways of the book
你就必须每天崇拜我
And you'll get to spend every day worshipping me
你会变得跟我们一样
You'll be just like us
真是的
Oh, gee
那是门铃吗
Is that the doorbell?
我  我好像忘关烤箱了
I-I think I left the oven on
听好  我的臣民
Listen, my people
书上说  现在是我的休息时间
the book says it's time for me to relax
在吗
Hello?
里面的都没事吧
Are you all right in there?
对对  我没事
Yes, yes, I'm all right
救我出来
Get me out
谢谢
Thank you
谢谢你们救我逃离这些傻
Thank you for rescuing me from these stupid--
你是章鱼哥吗
Are you Squidward Tentacles?
对
Yes
我们一直都在找你
We've been looking for you
我们是图书馆警察
We're the library police
你有一本借书已逾期30秒未还
You have a withdrawn book
that is now 30 seconds overdue
因此你必须受罚
And you'll have to pay the penalty
有什么惩罚
What do I owe you--
像是罚款一毛吗
like, a nickel?
你要进图书馆监狱
You're going to library jail
图书馆监狱
Library jail--
真是放松
how relaxing
我花时间养精蓄锐  以此赏识自己
"I appreciate myself by taking time to recharge
还陪着我最好的朋友
"with my best friend--
我
me"
睿智的大王啊  我们好想你
Oh, wise king, we missed you so
为什么  海神王
Why, Neptune?
为什么
Why?
我们也有书逾期了
We had overdue books, too
上楼
Going up
本集完